William Rich

Content Designer

in /in/williamrich3/

% +64 21 0841 9521

About Me

Experienced Content Designer with a demonstrated history of creating, designing, and delivering complete learning solutions to SaaS organisations. Strong visual design background; skilled in video production, animation, content creation, web editing, and project management.

Lead staff and customer education at Cin7 by independently producing over 300 videos and 70 education courses.

Worked alongside stakeholders and education specialists at Xero to produce consistent and beautiful customer-facing digital education content across a variety of formats.

Experience

Content Designer

Xero

June 2021 - Present | Auckland

- Assisting with the production (audio recording, screen capture, filming), and post-production (editing & motion graphics) of educational videos.
- Assisting with the build-out, testing and maintenance of eLearning content.
- Creating graphics, slides, artwork and illustrations for use in digital education projects.
- Producing animated videos (storyboarding, visual development, asset creation, animation, music, sound design), and animated motion graphics templates.
- Building and maintaining relationships with project stakeholders globally.

Digital Designer

Cin 7

October 2019 - June 2021 | Auckland

- Scripted, recorded, edited, and maintained the video content for the learning management system.
- Developed learning plans, courses, and curriculums that were designed for different learning styles.
- Worked together with the product teams to identify and address gaps in product knowledge through new learning content.
- Utilised a data-driven approach to decide upon new learning content.

Technical Support Specialist Cin 7

April 2019 - October 2019 | Auckland

- Provided advanced technical support which involved investigating, reproducing and resolving client software and hardware issues.
- Assisted with the training and onboarding of new support team members.

Education

BS, Computer Science
The University of Auckland

March 2015 - November 2018 | Auckland

BCom, Information Systems
The University of Auckland

March 2015 - November 2018 | Auckland

Exchange Programme
The University of Georgia

January 2018 - May 2018 | Athens

Current Projects

- Building my personal website, william-rich.com
- Coding an ELO rating calculator

Skills

Visual Design

Video Scripting/Recording/Editing

Animation

Data Analysis

Wireframing

Web Design

Sprint Methodology

Project Management

Tools

Figma	Miro	HTML
Illustrator	Salesforce	CSS
After Effects	Asana	Python
Premiere Pro	Jira	SOL